all right Nate tans been my brother give
me a fist pump right now to start this
thing off lock over the chair I love
[__] Jung card left podcast man I'm
happy to have you here I want to dive in
man like we just as soon as you got here
we just started just going into it we
just got so much so much like I wanted
the way that we were linked up or the
way that I like thought to message you
was I had multiple people a couple of my
friends who are like hey Nate Jasmine's
been really honest like his positive
like motivational game he'd be dope on
your podcast I'm like epic I looked at
your Instagram it was like oh man which
is great dude I love I love the fact
that that people can see that like so
much gratitude bro so so much gratitude
like the fact that people are
recognizing it is crazy to me because
I've been you're known for that because
I was known for the wrong things for so
long right yeah well well do you want to
talk about that so that flip from like
you know not not feeling you deserve to
be happy
you know these feelings you're going
through what what that flip that
happened what was that it was so it was
such a long process like really I think
the thing that really made me want to
change and that I woke up one day and
decided that it was time is that I hated
myself I hated the person that I was I
hated what I represented everything
about me I didn't like like I believe
that you're supposed to be your own
biggest hero like when you look in the
mirror you're supposed to be like okay
like I want to be like that guy right
and I never I never understood and I
never I never really figured out why but
I used to get ready for work in the dark
what in the bathroom yeah that's crazy I
was you didn't want to see the guy in
the mirror I would turn the light off
out until it's re I would turn the light
on outside of the bathroom so I could
see a little bit and I would get I would
get ready in the dark and I I never know
why and my girl at the time would always
come in and be like what are you doing
like turn the light on
I would like turn off I never know why
and I figured out that was it like I I
didn't want to look at myself I hated
myself that's so crazy and I didn't even
realize that it wasn't even while I was
doing it or the or the
the time that I changed it was until a
few weeks ago that I was like I
remembered that I used to do that and I
did it I did it for a year he's gonna
retrospect we'd be like why was I doing
that I did I did it for years I used to
roam the hall light outside the bathroom
and I'm going else in the dark
man all right what do you do now you
turn the lights on okay so give yourself
a finger girl yeah yeah yeah so that
that jump so why like if you feel like
talking about it why were you so down
like what why didn't you like yourself
is there things that you know listeners
may be able to relate to yeah absolutely
I think I was on this fast-track
lifestyle and I was living just everyday
by the seat of my pants and whatever was
giving me feeling of appreciation I
would I would jump right in to no
questions asked and at that time
everything was physical it was all flesh
it was a lot of girls which is I think
was my biggest thing that I was feeding
was was females right yeah it's so easy
to see it exactly it would feed my ego
all I wanted was affirmation from
somebody and so I found easy ways to get
it and if you're getting positive
affirmation from multiple streams at the
same time you must be doing good right
you must be is gonna keep you yeah
exactly you must I mean what do I need
to change everybody likes me you're the
best you're the best I'm the best I'm
the best right here you are getting
getting ready in the dark yeah who
didn't even realize exactly yeah
which is like I said which was crazy
because I didn't even know what was
going on I hadn't I haven't done that in
in probably close to a year and I just
figured out the other day like it came
to me and I was like whoa okay I used to
do that well good for you for pulling
out that mask you know that's something
that we do weird things to ourself think
that we deserve to fill certain ways
sometimes we don't realize we're doing
it to ourselves no idea so weird huh so
so you're just like weren't you you were
just living just for instant
gratification you're just trying to like
please your ego please might we chat a
little bit about ego before this you
won't touch on your ego how was your ego
different then
now I would say as far as like my my ego
is I still have it everybody's got it
like it never goes away
it's a hard concept to get around to me
to me the ego was a beast like you can
feed it good things you can feed it bad
things and I was feeding my ego so many
bad things I was constantly in challenge
I wanted to challenge everybody that
that didn't agree with me or that didn't
that didn't think how I thought it was
always a challenge the ego was if I have
this many women if I have this if I have
that if I have this car if I have this
if I have all this money whatever
whatever these things I must like I said
I must be doing good I must be fine now
I think my ego has shifted and to where
I don't want to say I don't have one but
I think it's because we relate ego to
negative I think my ego now is like my
ego doesn't allow me to you know let
people around me down my ego doesn't
allow me to I managed at the job that I
have I don't allow my teammates to get
down I don't allow like I take it
personal and I think that's where it
shifted it was then I started taking
things that I thought are now necessary
personal so I in those and my ego is all
of positive reinforcement instead of
negative I'm feeding a better cost than
a worse one I'm feeding the ego that
helps me grow and that helps everyone
around me grow and helps everyone around
me do better then crushing everyone
around me cuz that's what I was doing as
long as I was on top it didn't matter
where everyone else was that but now I
realize like you know we can all stand
on this podium like everybody fits
everybody can fit in first place like a
lot of people think a lot of people
think that that's not possible but it is
and I really think that if I'm if I'm
who I'm supposed to be and I'm the best
version of myself that I can bring
everybody else up there and that's what
I that's now my goal instead of because
I used to crush people I used to use
other people for what I could use them
for and as soon as that time was out now
you're no good to me right and that's
live like I said literally the exact
opposite now I try to even even when it
doesn't benefit me I'm still involved
because I think that I can help
everybody yeah simon Sinek talks about
using people seeing people as an end or
are a means to an end rather than and I
have freed exactly what and yeah an end
of something yeah but but you can't
you've got a tree every single person as
as an individual as as yes as deserving
just as deserving as loved as you are
yourself you know I can't treat him it's
like oh you're trying to get me I'm
trying to buy a Snickers bar and you're
the person in my way trying to get me in
the way of my stickers right now exactly
can't treat treat people like that so I
mean dude yeah you're hugely on this
positive thing now so you jumped from
from back then to now when did that
start you're 28 now yeah man
it was until last year yeah yeah
basically me dude it took me so long
dude s around the same time when I
started like getting better and yeah
really it took me so long
I had some really really really really
great people in my life a girl that I
was with at the time that was it was on
it was she was on this the same stuff
you know like positive change your way
of thinking change your way of that and
I looked at it every single time as a
challenge like you're challenging me
like I'm like I'm a grown man don't you
know don't talk to me like that don't
talk to me like this so talk to me like
like how are you gonna tell me I'm
messing up like I'm not like I'm you
know but she just wants better for she
wants better for me and then my mom has
always been a positive reinforcement mom
when I was little my mom like she told
me Nate the glass is half-full I'm like
mom I don't know what are you I don't
know what you're talking about right
like what glass there's no glasses like
there is no glasses and you understand
way later oh dude from I mean my mom was
telling me that it is as early as I
could comprehend words my mom was
telling me that and I never understood
it you know which my mom is like the
prime reason and and for me of doing
this because my mom grew up at by 16 was
an orphan living in a car working ha
like is my life that bad like no
absolutely not right like where's the
gratitude of it where's
your attitude of it and I think my mom
never turned to alcohol she never turned
her drugs she just did what she had to
do and I'm like there's no way that I
can with the life of I had a great life
I mean both my parents loved me I never
you know had any real trauma like any
traumatic like huge experiences and I'm
like how can I
how can I not keep going you know how
can I not how can I not have a different
perspective of life when somebody that's
so close to me struggled worked so hard
worked so hard struggled and hurt look
at her attitude I mean my mom is like
the most positive light of anybody that
I know and just spread so much love so
much joy like you know such an emotional
creature and I love that about her and
she always tried to instill that in me
and it was crazy and I think everything
happens for a reason but I if I could go
back and if it was one thing and I hate
to say the word regret but I have to
my mom would look at me when it I was so
I've always been so close to her and
during this time from dude it was long
19 to 26 was when I was really really
really like really bad and my mom would
look at me and she don't need that's not
how I raised to you hmm
like and that's not who you are like
your that's the what you're doing you're
not supposed to be that man and I'm like
no no you know like forget I don't need
anybody I don't I don't you don't get it
you don't get when I'm going through you
don't understand I don't I don't you
know I don't need women I don't need
feelings I don't need this I don't even
need you and and I'm like dude what yeah
though if there was one thing I could
change it would be that right but if I
didn't say that I feel so much more now
like I like I'm an emotional dude bro
like it things hit me yeah things hit me
and I'm like oh god you know so I think
if I didn't go through all that I
wouldn't be feeling the way that I feel
now and so I think that I had to and I
know that my mom
loves me unconditionally always you know
forgive me and I will never you know but
and you're doing right by a nothing
you've ever done yeah you know that's
what I can do you can't get a time
machine you don't have one yeah I can't
go back I just trying to move forward
yeah
just moving forward to your life man
dude it's so cool you're such a positive
like influencer now you know that's all
cool and it's really cool you know
you're starting like that you more
recently to your starting the whole
YouTube thing feel like this I said feel
like it's I feel like it's necessary
like I I have always always always been
into helping people like in I've always
like you know let me like talk to me you
know I love talking to people my mom
told me when I was seven years old she
said drop me off to get my hair cut
every time she picked me up she would be
like the lady would like dude this kid
is having a full-on conversation hole
like how old is he you know six seven
years old like I'm talking to adults
chick in people's hands like I've always
had that gift of connection yeah you got
this down I've always had that gift of
connection I can walk into any room and
connect with any person and I I denied
it for so I thought it was a weakness
because I'm like why do I feel nobody
else feels everyone else is hard like
everybody else is hard on the outside
why do I feel especially in high school
I had I was so emotional and I was like
putting on this you know this face and
this mask of you know I'm not like that
I'm big I'm hard I play sports you know
I do this I do that the ego the the ego
before was driving me to be a person
that I didn't want to be and and it kept
getting bigger and bigger and bigger and
bigger and bigger so it was it was just
it was tough but I you know I I feel
like I was not only I feel like I had a
gift but I'm like this hat like I have
to do this because the second that I
realized that I said I make money every
once in while with my camera but the
second that I've been written a cheque
or handed cash to make a video or to you
know do some sort of video production
and with my camera the feeling that I
get from posting a free YouTube video is
so much greater than money right it's a
rush like somebody out a friend text me
the other day and was like telling me
this long thing it was like hey you know
I
ran into an old friend who was on a
rough path before I was telling her
about your videos and I had her follow
you sure enough I go on there I checked
this person follow me I'm like dude I'm
like about like my eyes are like dude
I'm like I'm that guy like I'm like and
the fact that someone thinks about me
away from me you know and the fact that
someone whom like hey you're going
through a hard time I got a guy like the
fact that I got a guy and that's me yeah
uh that's unbelievable you can mumble in
everyday yeah okay why should I get up
today it's because somebody might need
me mm-hmm you know sometimes you know we
want to give ourselves more than that
but some days we can't yeah it's okay -
yeah else needs me today that's okay
exactly yeah I have this thing that I
say that I can be the proof and I it's
like it's like a I got all these
hashtags every single hashtag a hashtag
the same exact thing every time because
they all are close to me and it's
something that I've came up with that I
live by and it's like that you can be
the proof it's like you can show people
that it's possible to do whatever you
want to do in your line you're making a
podcast right you know you do music like
the motivation is there knowing the fact
that there's a kid that might be wanting
to give up on his music and maybe see
yours he might not like it there's a kid
out there that is like I really want to
record a podcast but I absolutely hate
my voice how am I gonna do it I didn't
say I'm you same thing he might look at
you and Jake you're the proof now you're
the proof that somebody else can do it
and so that's what I think when someone
needs you I think that's where that
comes from for me he's like yo I can be
the guy I didn't finish my a book from
cover to cover until two weeks ago I'm
28 years old
all right dude two weeks ago yeah what
was the book that you just finished uh
it was called the power of your
potential by John Maxwell it was an
image on what dude he it's he's an
incredible incredible author he's all
about leadership it was about basically
crushing limitations like exit there so
there was exercises in the book which I
really like because it was one of those
books where it's not a story it's it's
yes it's self-development but it's
information
I could close it not read it for five
days pick it up
start from the chapter and there was a
little you know I'm saying so it would
it's not gonna come who the character is
what am i exactly so it wasn't like I
was falling like an autobiography or
something like that or like oh this is a
motivational book but this book was like
it was it was so it was so great and I
was just so into it and I was like I
figured out why I never read a book
because I didn't care about what any of
these other books were telling me right
and so that when I shut that book I was
like dude it doesn't matter if people
barely graduate like it doesn't matter
if people don't read like yeah you can
still be something like I can show
people that I mean dude I barely
graduated barely biggest by the hair and
it was only because my girlfriend at the
time did my senior project oh yeah
good looks and if I were you know
because I didn't put in the work and I
it was like no I can't you know I'm not
gonna do that you know and so I go in
and then I've got you know no no formal
education at all I mean I go to college
mom you know I'm barely making I'm
getting c-minuses in every closet that
doesn't mean anything I can you know I
could show people that if you grind it
out and you follow your dreams like you
can do whatever you want like whoever
thought a guy that was embarrassed about
who he was can stand in front of a
camera and tell people about her
struggles you know or you can be the
proof yeah and you could flip who you
used to be too full of that quick yeah
you could say like I want to be this
person but I'm just not that person well
the thing is if you want to be that
person you can work to me there are that
person all right you are you are them
yeah that's you got to wake up every day
with we were talking about earlier you
mentioned you lean over to the left you
lean over the right yes how about
choosing what's know the woman feed you
know actually yeah every morning when I
wake up well yeah pretty much every
morning for the last year I get up out
of bed and I go like this I put my foot
on the floor and I go let's get this
Brett doing this this dorky ass thing
that I started doing to make Shaylee
laugh and now I do it when she's not
next to me and it gets me and it reminds
me like what am i today
you know like what bestow my feelings
there's more
routine is so important morning what you
dude alright let's talk about what you
want to so I don't have a specific time
that I wake up because I was so
exhausted for so long I physically
pushed myself I ride I go to the gym
last year I was working two jobs I was
working 60 hours a week I was three days
a week I was getting up at 3:30 to go to
the gym I just pushed myself to the
point of exhaustion and I I was I was
losing like I was I was working this you
know job and I was like I couldn't I
couldn't focus I was sitting at my
computer I was working behind a bar
after that I couldn't I couldn't keep
track of what was going on I wasn't you
were still fit through all this to thank
you still and that's what I was about to
touch on is that Iceland I literally
what I was trying to do was what's going
backwards like I was trying to do I was
trying to get lean and I was getting
soft like I was trying to gain size and
I was getting someone dude asleep is so
important my body was screaming at me I
I feel like there's obviously a reason
for and I haven't figured that out but I
feel like everybody holds stress you
know in a certain way I hold in my
forearms I would wake up and I couldn't
open and close my hands dude I I carried
icy hot in my pocket all day I would
just rub I see a flame and the more do
think yeah unbelievable
and I I ignored it of course I ignored
it you know I was riding using a mouse
and picking up bottles you know and
pouring drinks and do it I got to the
point I could barely hold the bottle in
my hand you got to wonder like our
stress like it's like it comes for the
things that we know it's like and know
you need your forms I know you need
those fingers man's coming like I let me
ruin your little route life like your
body will talk to you tell you what it
needs and it's a it was telling me that
I needed to rest and so now I I really I
really really really try to get rest
like I'm i'ma go go go kind of guy I
can't I can't ever sit still but I as of
like a few days ago I'm really
prioritizing sleep so sometimes I'll be
up until 3 o'clock 4 o'clock in the
morning cutting a YouTube video and if I
do I sleep you know until 8:00 if I can
get a decent amount of sleep I'll get up
at 4 or 5 I just it's so important
get up right after I get out of bed the
first thing I do every single day is
make my bed right away love it yeah the
first accomplishment of the day right
there the first W of the day yeah I mean
yep I get up out of bed as soon as I get
up I make my bed I go over to my have a
little bookshelf and there's a book that
I read daily messages there's a daily
message for every single day I read that
gets it just gets me going man it gives
me it's like the first thing if you wake
up in the morning and the first thing
you do is grab your phone ooh oh dude
it's ruined my days so many times the
first thing I do if I see a negative you
know that's the first thing that happens
in your morning your day shot yeah do
you put yourself in a place of like
fighting things that you didn't know you
were fighting you guys in some [__] I
wanna do today so consciously yeah yeah
you're already like no you know who you
are today is you're a Democrat you're
you got on Facebook and someone about
the Republican and they chose it for you
yeah they chose who you're gonna be for
the day for you yeah it's not fair don't
let don't let your phone or social media
take that [__] from and start your day
at least just wake up you know and just
give yourself 20 minutes stretch get
some coffee do something come so much
did you don't lay in bed huge on your
foot I've been trying to stay off my
phone for around two hours after I get
out completely good completely I will
get on after I read my little morning
message I will get on YouTube and I'll
listen to like podcasts or like an
inspirational speech but I don't get on
social media I don't respond to texts or
phone calls so it's been helping you
know you're unavailable and they didn't
do it so okay that's another thing
that's kind of hard for us to like work
with but as we've now had a few years
with social media we've had a few years
and it's like technology thing we're
settling in we're going for what's next
you know we can now be like all right
it's okay to not be available at all
times there's something a lot this last
year that my friends have been so great
with me about I was so nervous that
they're gonna hate me and not be my
friend because I couldn't respond to
their text all the time but I've like
gone days where I'm like I'm not
touching my phone all day because I'm
just trying to work and be in my own
mind using things oh yeah it's just
super okay so you
I don't wanna skip over your morning
so you don't jump on your phone no
matter what it's a new thing
yeah so every every once in a while I'll
break you know and I'm like oh I better
it's a work work tax or call I better
grab that but my goal trying my goal is
two hours yeah as is after I open my
eyes no social media no call no text
like I said if it's something more I see
a word where it looks like it's an
emergency I'll get it but I think it's
so important because I think we're so
addicted to our phones I think I mean
dude it's I think my phone right now is
my biggest weakness still at this point
and I'm not afraid to be vulnerable
about that yeah oh dude I'll walk around
pull out my phone like if I'm like I go
from my car to the to like inside the
gas station my phones in my hand I'm
like why why why dude I'll be I'll walk
outside to go like feed the squirrels
really you got your four minutes and I'm
like I need to listen to Alan Watts
performance yeah yeah or dude I was
thinking the other day I was talking to
somebody I'm like you know what do we
used to do in the car like when we do
have her phone like when we were young
what did you leave yeah like what did
you do did you well you know it is
something that I always think of like
what is history gonna say 100 years from
now and I'm always gonna say like it was
so bro like the iPhone and social media
it all just happened so fast there's
this is gonna be like a [__] on a
graph of timeline like history oh this
is gonna be like a blip of like we used
to do this and now we [__] do this
it's like completely changed yeah it's
in it's something that is like we got
caught up with this excitement you know
but it's it took it took a lot of
people's egos and like Windham [__]
right to the surface and I fit yeah I
think I think the cell phone too is kind
of like the wolf that we're talking
about though what are you gonna decide
to be one thing or the other we are in a
world right now where technology is
amazing and we use it for the most
negative things mm-hmm technology
creates more sadness depression all that
kind of stuff and it creates happiness
and money and jobs if if you have a cell
phone right now in 2019 you can be a
millionaire but we're all addicted to
the negative which like I battle that
totally with the tunur personally
I'm back on social media right now like
cuz I'm like oh I'm releasing my podcast
yeah but I also know that I'm like hey
yeah give me like its give me likes like
man my dope for me I'm just like please
dude it's crazy crazy yes you gotta be
aware of its that that approval yeah
like that I'm doing something that I
love I hope you like it
alright and it's it's it's a beast in
itself it's a beast in itself I find
it's not why you're posting that thing's
not wastefully you listen I Eric Thomas
he's a motivational speaker I yes he's
always clipped in with like good morning
motivational he's he's my Michael Jordan
oh no I
dude I searched for my Michael Jordan my
whole life I'm like who's my Michael
Jordan I don't know I you know I I like
sports but I like like who's my Michael
Jordan's guys he's my Michael Jordan I
was listening to a podcast of his and he
was saying a stop scoreboard watching
play the game don't post the video and
refresh refresh refresh I used to do
that when I posted my first video dude
every five seconds refresh one more view
one more view one more view if I stop
and I wait a week and then I go look at
it I'm gonna have as many views as I'm
gonna have and I'm not gonna be anxious
and have his anxiety was about at once
in between - exactly instead of
obsessing obsessing yeah it was a cool
little thing it hit me I love analogies
like that like I was like whoa and then
say give me some feeling on your like oh
I shoot I needed to hear that like what
am i doing what the heck exactly as I'm
doing it yeah - I'm like I don't know I
mean I'm aware of like my own excuses to
myself and my own justifications but I I
was off social media for about a year
okay and I was doing I mean I'm that's a
long time I did three months once yeah
bro and it seems like it's crazy because
my life flip right and I go back to
social media and there's a lot of things
that I do still love like I like like
there's a lot of things that I'm like oh
that's still super cool there's a lot of
things that affect changed even yeah
but I'm kind of trying to watch myself
like let's just let myself rip and just
see what the beast is doing like I'm
like up here observing myself on social
media right and it's like it's strange
man it's a it's a we can edit this out
if it's not part of your thing but like
I'm doing No
- okay and so just trying not to
masturbate okay and just like trying to
make it to where and the reason for that
is as simple as when an urge comes up
that's like say the wrong beast yeah I
say you can suppress it I say no if that
ain't me today the mind suppressing it
it's a it's a little win its wins you
know it's crazy that you say that I'm
actually on a little celibate kick right
now yeah yeah he's a different cognitive
differences sex drove my life for so
long all I ever wanted to do was conquer
conquer conquer if I can meet you and
get you as a woman in your most
vulnerable state right feeding you
[__] I'm powerful
crazy isn't that crazy
that's how I thought like I'm I'm you
know I am Who I am and and what was
crazy as I finally realized now that I
you don't realize things until you step
away so once I got out of my last
relationship I decided that I was going
to be celibate until I was going to
really really really be with somebody I
was not gonna have casual sex which I
it's been almost four months now what
wouldn't you know no sex no sexual
contact at all so you know I step back
from these things and I was like yo what
and I really love now analyzing myself
even the hard even the hardest things
even the things that people are like I
would never say those things about
myself those are the things you have to
say I was I was a monster I was an
absolute monster I was just drawing
every person that I came in contact with
a woman in my path and I sat back and as
I'm you know in my celibacy I was like
dude you had this gift the whole time
and you were using it for the wrong
thing I had energy I had a gift of
connecting to emotion
mmm that's how I got what I wanted I had
a gift of letting people feel me and
feel my energy and get you know and
using it in a negative way and so I was
like you know this is a new thing like I
just you know came on this you know
thing where I'm
talking to people and helping no I was
always doing that I always possessed
this gift but the other beast used it
dude is your intelligence like what's so
true to you and set well no it like
tricks you it's almost your intelligence
is good you almost your intelligence is
like I think it's like Jafar yeah
intelligent yeah yeah and he's like he's
got your [__] Lane yeah it's and it's
it's like it's like the the devil and
the angel on one on each side it's like
okay this is who you are I did but I did
I didn't even know you don't realize it
I had no idea I was like I was like I
was like I'm good with women like okay
right like there's a lot of other people
that are too I had no idea the extent of
how deep that I could go with I call it
now a gift but before you know I was
using in the wrong way so I don't know
what to call it for then but I mean I
have people that I have tried to reach
out to to apologize because I I really
feel that I I put people through a lot
of stuff and I've tried to apologize to
a few of my exes and some of them are
like you know really grateful for the
apology they moved on with their lives
and it's been five six seven years for
some people and some of them still
haven't right never like leave me alone
you ruin my life
and I'm like I hadn't with that live
with that big of an impact in the wrong
way yeah and and now you know I could
let it be like a cloud over me and and I
could use it you know as a crutch and
and make excuses but now I'm like in a
positive way imagine what I can do you
know imagine what I can do imagine how I
can make you feel like given my
experiences imagine how I can help you
with your life and I think I'm trying to
figure out a different word than
motivational speaker because I want to
help people success is not what's
important to me and I think a lot of
people think that well if you're a
motivational speaker you need to be
successful I want to get people out of
their holes right that's all I want
like I want to get people I want to
change their perspectives I want to get
people out of their holes I want to get
people feeling positive that's what I
want I don't I don't care about money
care about materials I don't care about
anything about that let's see if I can
get on the biggest stage I want a one
day perform at this place like nobody
yes and I but I think I think that's
part of my journey still I really do I
think that if I can hone in my craft and
I can hone my gift I think that without
trying I think that will happen for me
I really do it I'm a firm believer on on
there is no limit I mean everything that
I've ever wanted to do that I've really
really set my mind I've done so why can
I do something big
well okay so let's you know we were kind
of talking earlier about you know
schools you know eventually you know
maybe even like small companies like if
you want to talk like whatever like are
you open to any listeners if they want
like a speaker's hundred percent yeah
hundred percent
no charge get me in there yeah bro yeah
all right cool yeah if you guys need a
speaker maybe just reach out if a
specific subject that you may know about
yeah what's your let's plug so we don't
have YouTube is nasty Nate YouTube's my
Instagram is at nasty Nate underscore
junior yeah look me up on Facebook at
Nicene 8 underscore junior yeah dude
let's get you on some stuff and I want
to you know obviously like throughout
our life if like this is going to be a
dope positive connection absolutely yeah
obviously like Sibbett so we can get you
on here monster mama if you got some
messages I'm sure I love you yeah doing
more and so I wanted I actually do want
to talk about motorcycles so I actually
probably didn't know I grew up around
motorcycles my parents were in it was
the calots county abate I don't know if
you know anything but it was ah more
like the Harley world okay um but like
so when I was younger I was on the back
of motorcycles all the time it was like
my whole life yeah a lot of my family it
still is one of their life but it's
funny not funny just interesting mm-hmm
I've never been like a daredevil type
okay and so I thought that that was like
why I was like like bikes are cool but
I'm not like it was never jumped into it
was but it was kind of me veering away
from my family so it was like anything
to do with them absolutely so it was
kind of an actual thing and so more
recently I'm like man there's a lot of
things that are beautiful that I'm not
seeing as beautiful because I threw them
into a pot you know we're know things
that were
connection to a negative yeah so so I
and I was thinking about it just
yesterday I was think about it with math
Maddox I actually have like a weird I
think mathematics are like like how
things always work out where's it's so
fascinating and it's it's the mo it's so
beautiful I don't understand how it's
beautiful cuz I don't know mathematics
yeah so I'm on a quest like I have like
people who like mathematician friends
who I want on here because I want to
understand how oh your math is beautiful
so from someone who has never let's say
that like I've really never felt like
the the oneness of me writing alone on
an open highway loca like how is riding
a motorcycle beautiful oh dude for me I
like I said I think with the way society
is the way that we're we're put on this
train right like when you grow up unless
you have you know a a you know a
difficult life or or your parents you
know push you in different direction
generally most kids are put on a train
to all go the same way you're supposed
to go to school right you know you go
you go to school you do this you do that
you know I feel like there's a mold
right I never fit in that mold like I I
found my whole life I never fit in this
mold and instead of it capitalizing on
it cuz I'm like I should have been like
yo this is great I'm not like everybody
else but instead I thought it was a
failure I was like you know I was I was
okay at I wouldn't I'm really hard at
myself so I would say I was I was
decently skilled in sports I just worked
really hard I think it was it wasn't the
actual sport it was that I wanted to
succeed the fact that I wanted to you
know I just wanted to be good at
something so if I work my ass off which
I've always done and everything that
I've ever wanted I worked my ass off
like I made sure that I was working the
hardest or I was working with the people
that were working the hardest so if I
had this you know accomplishment I would
feel good even when I had the
accomplishment I was just like uh you
know whatever that's cool the same thing
I was you know my parents are like you
know if you try and get get great then
I'm like you know whatever like I would
get I would like oh I get like a B and
from a you know from enough I get a B
and I'm like
well now what you know yeah where is the
feel-good I could never focus that's why
like I still was saying I never read a
book dude I can never focus on one thing
the day that I got on the bike was the
first time in my life that I've ever
been fully 100% present hmm
100% I'm not thinking about anything
else other than the bike like how it
sounds how it feels
everything about it it's the one thing
that has makes my mind blank and I think
what's beautiful about it is that though
I'm not like a an open highway kind of
rider like I liked I ride wheelies and
stuff like that and it's just as
reckless as what I do is in the fact
that so much could go wrong that thought
never crosses my mind not once like I
never think about what can go wrong I
just think I'm like this is what I'm
supposed to do yeah like in every single
time I picked the front wheel up it
feels like the first time and I'm like
never never never do I get an off
thought and when I do because I have is
when I is when I mess up is when I go
down is when you know something and I'm
like whoa and it's a wake-up call it's
like I feel like it's teaching me so
much about life like if you want to be
good at something if you want something
to live like I want my riding and my
skill to live I have to be present with
it and I have to give it what it needs
and so right now when I'm in a wheelie
it needs my focus you know and I think I
can if I can take that up everywhere if
I can take that everywhere mmm with me
like I don't know but like I said first
time that I've ever been fully fully
fully present is when the front wheels
in the air and nothing else has crossed
my mind and it was the greatest feeling
hey yeah I'll have to because I you know
I I have ridden motorcycles like since
that since I was like what you know
littler and I do I don't know I've
gotten the enjoyment of the the fast
snowboarding so that's snowboarding like
just by myself I get it there but
there's something about by
that I still want but like obviously
hearing you talk about it I get it like
I feel like when you said it's like one
the moment I felt present that's what it
is
yeah that's that's what everybody has
like something but like what it is is as
a human like I think we're able to just
mine all these crazy things and you have
more than one something like yeah you
could you know maybe like in six years
it's rock climbing or something yeah and
just discovering those things like
because when it clicks you know for me
music like obviously that was my thing
and that's what it was I didn't really I
couldn't explain it that way at that at
that time when I first that's what it
was I was like an hour go by and I'm
like what that that felt what happened
like that was cool yeah it's it's not
until you I feel like you need a little
more mentally mature that you can
actually explain it cuz I you would have
asked me when I first started at 19 I
would have said I love the adrenaline
you know I love the adrenaline but the
adrenaline comes from the concentration
and the concentration comes from being
present so I think that's what really
really drives me and to keep doing it is
that well it's not what you do isn't
just showing off because you what you do
takes a lot of practice yeah so like the
hours and hours and the pains and the
pains and then probably the money that
you have to spend I imagine on like
Wilson sir band par so the the thing
that I love most about stunt riding and
I think the thing that has drawn me so
much to it is the culture like there
don't get me wrong there's there's a
pretty big handful of people that get
paid for what they do but I would say
with all stunt riders about 90 percent
don't make a dime ever off any kind of
money off stunt riding so when you can
have a sport where dudes are flipping
their bikes down the freeway and getting
back up and getting back on it for not a
dime but because they love it I mean
where can you get that I always use this
analogy like you can't you can't go to
the local YMCA and play basketball
without somebody talking [__] to you
that's a nobody but you can go on the
biggest in the biggest stage I've rode
with guys that when I first when I first
bought a motorcycle I literally typed in
how to wheelie like I was watching dudes
making videos learning how to wheelie I
rode with those guys I wrote at their
facilities I've been on the
rides I've been in their YouTube videos
like where can you do that kids are
looking up to LeBron they're not gonna
play basketball it's LeBron you know I
mean I'm not saying that these guys are
my heroes but I'm saying these are the
dudes that I looked up to the pioneers
to my game and they let you right in and
just they know because I earned my way
in and they know what it takes when you
are good at this sport as long as you're
not a piece of [__] you get respect
because it the injury the time the money
the difficulty all the things like you
don't even if I knows if I know if I
look at somebody else they're good
respect right away because I know what
I've been through and everybody else
knows what they've been through they
have their own struggles some people you
know some people are just naturally
gifted I know dudes that you know I've
had very few crashes and just kill it
and do tricks that nobody else can do
and I know other dudes that you know
I've been ran over by cars and I know
other dudes that you know I mean have
had broken bones bone after bone after
bone and so when you're good there it's
the respect is there and that's why even
the dudes that get paid for it still
ride with the dudes that don't when
they're good because of the respect and
it's still a culture it's still like has
a family yes I mean you know every every
every group thing has its beef and every
group thing has its [__] but I would
like to say that it's it's a good
culture I really do I think there's a
solid solid a good solid group of dudes
that ride that I that I enjoy riding
with and dudes that are on a similar
positive train as me and trying to you
know not only better themselves on the
bike but off the bike too because I
think that's really important I think I
got better riding when I got better off
the bike I really do yeah because my
that's how life works yeah it really is
crazy I used to get I used to get like
performance anxiety like I would when I
first started riding I had no fear like
you know 19 20 21 years old I'm like
wasn't gonna happen I can like break you
know break my neck like whatever yeah
and as I started to get older a little
bit like I think
it was last year when I had this you
know I had a great job I had a big house
I was living in I had you know a girl
and we were you know we're getting
married and I feel like I
I started thinking while I was riding
and that really bothered me and that
bothered me can't be present if you're
thinking about the future exactly so the
second I started doing that I started
crashing I started you know had you had
a bad a bad crash yes a bad one mm you
want to touch on that 2015 I'm doing I'm
all out guy like if I'm if I do it I'm
doing it yeah I was working at Nike at
the time at the Downtown Nike store my
friend called me is like hey we're going
to Fresno tomorrow you in or not I'm
like bet I called out I left work that
day I said I was sick left work called
out the next day took literally all the
money I had to the penny spent it to go
on this trip we get their local show up
they're like yo the cops are crazy here
like whatever you do just be careful
because when you go to a stunt ride like
you unload your bike and that's your
means of transportation like you don't
really drive around because we all you
know we all haul our bikes that there's
six dudes in a car and we got six bikes
we're not taking one car we're taking
six bikes locals are like cops are crazy
we're like all right whatever you know
we're from Washington
yeah yeah we're from washing right so we
put the bikes in the street we and we're
doing what we do and everybody wheelies
we're out of town everyone's wheeling
all the time cuz it's not it's not art
you know it's not our town you guys have
helmets on to you oh yeah
yeah a hundred percent and we're not but
five minutes into this ride and they can
here come the cops and I so first ride
I've ever been on like big group ride
and so I'm like dude I don't know what
to do he's right behind me wants me cuz
I put it down last so I take off by
myself big mistake you always stay with
the group always always
you just clump together stay with the
group I take off by myself going down
the freeway
get off off-ramp there's a cop waiting
there
I jumped the curb next street there's a
cop waiting there I go down this side
street I'm I'm doing 90
in a 40 jumping these big speed bumps on
a street bike dude it was insane to get
to the end of this long road there's
another cop waiting there and then I
turn and I'm like okay if I can beat
this light I should be cool I didn't
know there's a helicopter above me but
yeah so I'm like if I can beat this
light I'll be good right so I'm like
going light turns yellow light turns red
and I'm coming through the intersection
I think you know how it is in Cali it's
not Washington like people are gonna go
people really are hurry this is somebody
light going exactly so as soon as it
turned red this person went and I
smashed into the car I think the higher
power whoever it is that the universe
God whoever it may be I don't know yet
that I didn't hurt the person in the car
because that would have that would have
that would have ruined me I hit the very
front of the car by the headlights kind
of like tipped off ended up smashing
into a curb and just tumbling I was
going like any I know I was going 90
before I got to the light I don't know
if I hit the brakes I'm sure I did it's
a it's a natural reaction yeah so anyone
anywhere from yeah anywhere from 60 to
you know up and I just tumbled in
tumbled and tumbled and tumblin it felt
like everything was like as fast as I
was going if I like everything was
moving slow and the only thought that
popped into my head is I was like dude
when you're done rolling you might be
dead like I don't know if like I like a
roll let's go crazy dude like a rag doll
like a rag doll was a hundred feet do
you feel like you so like you think like
you can do anything
no you couldn't I couldn't stuff you
feel like you controlled your crash at
all cuz I no no no no you know I was a
hundred feet away from my bike and the
bike was 50 feet away from the curb
would that I hit so the next thing I
know I'm like I'm laying there they they
got me they got me in handcuffs the
stick we put me on a stretcher
put you know take me the hospital
handcuffs how much ya in that situation
I mean
when your rather than cops yeah really
wait and it's funny because they were
like that's not funny I want to say that
yeah why you're white why are you
running why are you running you got a
gun you know you got priors bubble I was
like I'm from Washington and I didn't
want you to take my bike and they were
like a dude what it gave you a ticket
and I'm like wait hold up is it a lot
are the laws different familiar no but
the fact that I went they just they have
so much more to worry about pushing Cali
hear it more see here you run from the
cops here they're taking you to jail
yeah generally in Cali if you're doing a
wheelie and you set it down they usually
will let you skate if they got something
else to do if they got time they'll you
know they'll make your life health
situation it's situational so they take
me to the hospital I'm handcuffed to the
to the chair dude I got two broken hands
I tore ligaments in my ankle my ankle is
like not broken but it's just hanging
because all the ligaments are torn you
know left hip ligaments torn of the left
hip in the groin like dude I can't feel
my leg and they dude comes over in the
nurse he's like he's like dude you all
right
I had road rash from my hip all the way
up to my armpit at my left side all over
the front of me from grass so that's how
fast I was I was rolling it was from the
grass yeah
well imagine if he was cement I mean
done goodness yeah I'm lucky
um and dude is like you know are you
good and I'm like where's my bike and
he's like what and I'm like dude where's
my bike like I got a good like it we got
it like someone's gotta get my bike like
cops are gonna take it I'm in shock
obviously right you know some one thing
you're like yeah oh sorry that one-track
mind on that yeah and he's like it he's
like dude we don't even know if you're
like internally bleeding or not he's
like don't worry about your bike my girl
comes in there screaming right at the
girl at the time comes in screaming and
she's like are you okay are you okay
okay like obviously I'm okay I'm not I'm
not dying you know we know that but of
course she was panic but I just was like
just tell me I'm gonna build a ride
again
please please tell me I'm gonna build a
ride and she was it she panicked she was
young so I don't you know it's a panic
situations you know you didn't look too
great to know yeah they put me full
through a full body scan dude no neck
injuries no back injuries I mean my back
was a little crooked but nothing broken
took me out as soon as I got out of the
full body scan if you're not dying
they'll take you to jail took me to jail
I was in the I was in a holding cell for
like a day and a half they finally got
me in the medical wing and the nurses
were like we can't take care of you you
need to be in a hospital like you are
far - yeah yeah so you transport it back
yeah so my thank God I have a supportive
family my dad flew down to Fresno and
bailed me out yeah well it was dude like
I having so much gratitude broke because
I was so hurt in there I couldn't the
biggest biggest mental like struggle
I've ever been in in my life like I was
in a wheelchair
I can't move one leg the other foot is
just like dude like like I said I kind
of like hanging off they didn't clean my
Road Rash in the hospital so I was
turning green and it was starting to
smell and get infected another thing I
had - two broken hands and I did I was
getting to the point where I like if I
didn't stand up and like I was using the
phone cord in my in my holding cell to
pull myself up on my broken hand to use
the bathroom or I was gonna have to piss
on myself this variable but now it's
crazy because I just dropped this video
today shameless plug about how about
that about about remembering that that
time and like when I have times that I
can't get out of bed and I'm like dude
you had two broken hands all these
injuries you flew 150 feet on a bike and
you can't get out of bed yeah and you
picked yourself up with a phone cord oh
yeah come on bro yeah you must have
forgot yeah you must have four
about this you control this body you're
in control you're in control and if you
want to do it you can if you don't and
that's as funny is that I always tell
myself like if you don't want to do it
then don't say you do like you don't
have to be a motivational speaker you
don't have to want to inspire the world
but in doing that you know it comes
great responsibility and that means you
got to get out of it you gotta get out
of it you have step into that light you
got to step into that and I think
there's big shoes to fill in whatever
that is and I always tell myself I'm
like dude if you don't want to stop
saying you do right if you want to them
do something but that's the thing if
there's you know there's this because
there's a lot of other people just like
you and I who have this like little
voice that's like oh you've got to be
doing this like you have or it's
happening right but you still don't
think that it's you exactly like I would
you know post something on Facebook and
it's like yeah you know that was
heartfelt and it would be like true but
it would I wouldn't want to go much more
than that cuz I'm a cool my to tell
anybody what to do Who am I to give
advice I would look at my fault and be
like dude I suck like obviously I don't
know what the hell I'm talking about
because I suck and you know all these
things you gotta yeah step into it I
have those doubts all the time like I
think the second that I can have those
doubts and I can personally get rid of
them is that is that is the moment when
I'm really just gonna start killing it
like absolutely just murdering it
because what steps me out of there is
the times like I said when people will
call me and say hey you know I just
showed so-and-so your video I'm like yo
that's why you doing it like I have you
know a few people have probably like ten
people that are consistently every
single time I post they share it every
single time I post a mess and we joke
that message was even better than the
last one like you know when I honestly
it's probably more than ten which is
which is awesome to say but I feel like
I'm not gonna reach my full potential
until I don't need that and I think
because it's still a form of somewhat
instant gratification I wouldn't say
instant but it's an affirmation of
you're doing a good job keep going I
have to keep going regardless
aye aye aye I do the same thing because
I get people who messaged me in to you
to say the same thing like I've I've
I've legitimately saved multiple lives
and be a pop told me now that what I've
said is safe yeah I think I'm still even
after the moment even like those random
phone calls yeah I happened to be the
one who answered yes and it's it's like
whoa it's like a shaky thing it's just
well I got that that was me but but
stepping into those is like this whole
this whole thing you got to take
responsibility for the house like you
don't have that when you have that voice
that tells you that you should be doing
it anyway your life doesn't get better
when you ignore in that voice when you
try not drown it out yes the other wolf
huh
it just doesn't get any better I've and
you know what's crazy is like sometimes
I'm like whoa like do I want that like
that's huge like you're almost putting
someone else's life in your hands right
and and that's like I said with with
that greatness comes responsibility and
sometimes you're not sure if you can
handle that responsibility like what if
someone's looking forward to do
something I have to say and I you know
when I say it the wrong way or I and
that's where I we talked about earlier
about you know ignoring you know the
voices in your head because it's like
just do it
just put it out and I feel like the
authenticity is what is necessary
because if I'm not authentic if I'm not
I might speak something the wrong way or
I might not get my message across the
way I wanted to get across and then you
know I then I regret it then you know
then this and there's more voices more
voices more voices like but if you're
just a hundred percent present like you
know like we talked about a hundred
percent authentic I feel like you can't
go wrong because the people that need to
hear you somehow will hear you and I
don't mean that in like a they're gonna
watch your video away I mean that like
they're gonna really feel it like
because there's a difference between
less than a year there's a difference
between listening is something and
hearing something hearing it that's one
thing that like as I've been listening
to more YouTube videos and lectures and
like reading audiobooks and stuff the
amount of times that I rewind that thing
thing cuz I'm like man I heard that but
you didn't I didn't listen here yeah
yeah or like you didn't hear that
there was something in me that's like
that was a ridiculous and profound thing
to hear you need to get that twice oh do
you know we're not highlighted or
something - and it's it's crazy because
sometimes I feel like that that
statement that people always say is like
less is more so true like I have like
I'll read like a like a two-word quote
and I'm like whoa what in the hell or
you know or someone will say something
that's like so simple like that Eric
Thomas thing you know that was like you
know just play the game to look at the
scoreboard and I was like oh wow like
what am i quirky core that's pulling you
out of your game man yeah I'm like where
you come up with that like you know it's
crazy
so yeah well it's cool you know what
it's cool because how you're mentioning
his name like what the podcast of
whatever the hell podcasts are in 15
years know like like that's that's your
name and their mouth potentially I know
and that's and that's what I yeah honey
% so I'm like that's that's the dream
and it's the goal well well I'm the
action dude I I'm happy to be like a
little stepping stone of it I'm happy to
like be on it with you and so whatever
so yeah yeah I do want to we've been up
here for a while but I do want to touch
on Fitness a little bit if you got it in
yeah bro
so I got so what's your what's your
background of fitness like you're
obviously like a pretty in shape do bar
you are you a coach - are you training
no I seem like it I originally got into
fitness I started lifting weights in
sixth grade okay
um it was the ego that's what started it
that's what started it so that you the
ego was what was driving it the ego was
like you know I gotta be big I gotta be
real and we grew up in this small town
where yes not that yeah you gotta be you
gotta prove the urine your presence your
presence yeah and that's for Jax and
exactly yeah I feel like I had to give
off a flesh physical presence if I
didn't give off that presence people
shallow people wouldn't even want to
talk to me or wouldn't even want to get
to know me or wouldn't like me because I
didn't have this great physical presence
and so the ego is what drove the the
love and then I wouldn't even call it a
love cuz you don't have to if you love
something you just do it it was a need
there was a need I was needing
to be in shape I was needing to workout
I was needing a little weight I was
needing to be huge and in doing that I
caused myself a lot of injury I mean at
in 2000 it was the same year I got my
accident 2015 I was lifting for
absolutely nothing but trying to out
lift a dude next to me and trying to
impress the girl that was gonna be in my
life for a week and I was 140 pounds
squatting like 345 350 just cuz I mean
for what I'm not a bodybuilder like I'm
not a power lifter so crazy it wasn't it
was an ego thing it was I can so I could
say I could do it and that's what was
feeding it and now it's completely
flipped yeah so how are you my mean cuz
you're still like you still have you
didn't throw away all of working out
you've now got this this health in it so
how are you now what's the difference
between you lifting back then and now
when your mind into the present
100% based on my performance needs on my
bike and what my body needs so I still
like is more important to you you said
like this is not just about fitness yes
100% yeah yeah the bike is way more
important but the the fitness is to me
is a part of the bike I think that's
what separates full circle a lot of
great riders I think the stunts seen in
overseas is is like years and years
ahead of America we have dudes in it
overseas that are just absolutely like
levels and levels ahead of the guys in
America which there's a few guys that
are competing in those stunt shows and
stunt competitions in Europe but the
amount of riders that they have that are
at the skill level is insane compared to
over here and I think a lot of those
dudes a lot of the guys that I really
love to watch ride or athletes they rock
climb they stretch they workout they do
yoga things that we totally take for
granted I'm like we're like we don't
want to do yoga but everybody wants to
be flexible and nobody wants to do yoga
and I did yoga right there for 30
minutes before you guys I mean like and
I think working out and eating right is
a really really big important part of
stunt riding when you want to perform at
a high level I think honestly a lot of
people just do it for fun which is which
is absolutely fine but I
I do it because I have this bond with
stunt riding that I've rode with dudes
that I used to look up to I've proven to
myself that I can do tricks that people
think art that you know that can't be
done or you can only do it a certain way
and I've done it differently so I've
been to jail I've been I've had injuries
like I've tongue I've come too far to
turn back like I have this bond with it
and so in that bond
I do everything that's necessary to be
better at it so I try I do my training
instead of lifting heavy weights I do
it's all according to balance core
stability of course I still still like
to slang weights every once in a while
because it's cool you know it's it's you
know it's good to just like like feel
exhausted after yeah yeah I just got
some [__] up yeah and I I still I still
go so hard I still go so hard but uh I
just changed it up I change it to what
works for me and what I need instead of
that ego I mean I was lifting like a
bodybuilder I'm not a body Miller my
stunt rider
like what like why you know I was
isolating muscles you know chest chest
on chest drawers on Monday you know I'm
saying I've been there yeah so now I'm
I'm on a little bit of a different
program it's still weights but I do a
lot of calisthenics a lot of pull-ups a
lot of push-ups a lot of bodyweight
stuff yeah seems like you probably slow
it down then to your it's still still
high-intensity and I do a lot of yeah I
still do a lot of super setting just
because I absolutely hate cardio so I
try to do I try to work out faster yeah
like hit up man hey yeah it's great yes
and I uh
with my back I've been I can't I would
love to sprint because I really want to
be athletic that's my goal and I think
being athletic on the bike is really
really important I think that it helps
your movements so I can't sprint with my
back so I just started swimming actually
today and so that's gonna be a new yeah
I've heard great things about that'll be
a new thing in my program full body
workout with the swimming and that's how
I do my cardio now from now on a
swimming well next podcast we're gonna
have to get an update on this swimming I
want to know about you I mean I'm all
about like the cool thing about its
podcast is I get to mine cool people for
how they handle this crazy brain that we
all have you know yeah and so I'm like
oh I can try
yeah absolutely yeah it's so cool that
that's crazy cool do you have any you
know like you've always been so we
actually worked out at I remember you
were kind of forever fit right yeah yeah
so I remember I'm sure I just have this
image like we don't know each other
super well in the last few years but we
didn't know each other it was always
like DAPs up at the gym you don't always
see the gym you're always getting it
they know had you on social media yeah
always still care yeah so just as you
know not claiming to be a fitness coach
whatever I want I want my podcast to
often be a brand from nothing to
something absolutely like people who
have never worked out day in their life
people who want to get healthy they want
to yeah just just get more get healthier
yes like like what could you recommend
like maybe a stepping stone like from
nothing to something absolutely Fitness
is like I said I was talking about
making my bed every morning the first
the first one in the day I think
exercise is a is in that same category
but in a different way I firmly think
that mess will be comes before physical
always always but in that physical you
get the mental winds so I think that
exercising gives me that sense of
accomplishment I like to go to the gym
in the morning lately I've been going
really late at night like 10:00 p.m. and
I'll get done in like midnight or
sometimes even midnight till 2:00 in the
morning but when I go first thing in the
morning and I get in there and get after
it dude I feel so good I love them I
feel dude I feel so good like I feel
like I'm like wow my day
I already got up already made my bed
already read my word I already read my
affirmation for the day and now I just
worked out like how I'll call and that
is a lot of people get stuck especially
with weight and being overweight right
they get stuck you know all you need to
know dude oh it's all you have to do is
get momentum yeah yeah all you have to
do is push the snowball down the hill
yeah push it it's heavy it's like when
you push a car right you ever pushed a
car that was in neutral sure do when you
and you're moving around and like and
you're you turn around you try to put
your back against it yeah this second
the wheels start rolling once you get it
going
done then you got one hand you got to
your bone you know what every dance
around it spin around yeah yeah it's
momentum and I think that's a huge
part of fitness it's it's so hard to get
started and after I was injured I was
like dude I don't even want to go back
like I don't like I I'm gonna go in
there and lift no zero no weights right
what do you mean no weights yeah I don't
want to restart this thing no so I I
literally was so discouraged when I
first was healed and was okay to go to
the gym I didn't go the doctors like you
know how was it cuz I mean when I came
in there I was in good shape you know
and then when I was got my cast off
they're like okay like I let myself go
right you know I was like oh like I was
on I was on the train I got off the
train and it felt like the train was
moving so fast and I wasn't gonna be
like get back on it so I just let myself
go I started eating horrible and it
wasn't like I said it's it's the mirror
bro I was until I looked in the mirror I
was like dude look at you then I like
you right now like is that all you it's
out all you got is that all you got like
you weren't you know like that you're
gonna let that like you're gonna let
this determine the rest of your life and
I finally got back in the gym and I
finally I had it and I think that was
the first thing of me let my ego go was
I walked in the gym I would be working
out with my girl and she would you know
you know she in good shape strong I mean
like squatting like you know twenty
fives on each side 95 pounds sometimes
the 35 is 145 we'd have to take the
weights off so I could squat oh that's
rough yeah you know that that's rough
for a masculine yes no doubt and at one
point I when I first got back into it I
was not even using the bar I'd go inside
the squat rack to to air squat were you
in pain through a lot of this too oh
yeah absolutely like physical therapy
food dude and it's crazy because I it
was such a long journey I lifted no
weights for like six months I was doing
like deadlifts and one legged deadlifts
and on [__] with just body weight I was
you know I could only like pret if I
wanted to lift weights I mean I could do
leg curls and all that kind of stuff but
as far as like any weights big weights
lake press was the only thing I could do
because of my back so but you still got
in there but I still got in there
in the second that I checked my ego and
I think this goes back to that we're
talking about when you're young you
don't process things and you don't
really get it but basketball coach coach
back amiss
we used to go in the weight room used to
say leave your ego at the door and I'm
like dude why is this guy talking about
what is this guy talking about he's nuts
like yeah I get it
these nuts and I'm like all right
whatever coach you know right now I get
it
and I'm like what teachers have that
magic but they insert something and I'd
of us that we don't know ten years later
but I can't once I get to be a better
Houston I am more sure of myself that I
can do them no harm in any way I want to
have some my old teachers on here in
that same way yeah absolutely
some of those yeah yeah he and the first
the first day that I walked in there and
I was like I had to sit in the car i sat
in the car for 30 minutes and I was like
this is it like you're about to go in
there you're not gonna put any weights
on people are gonna think you're weak
people are gonna judge you mm-hmm you
can either start now or you can start
tomorrow and then tomorrow becomes the
next day and the next day and the next
day and the next day and then we've
already waited three months so today's
the day and I walked in there and I
walked in the stood under the school in
squat rack with no weights on there and
then loaded it up for my girl it killed
me at first and then I was like people
don't know people don't know what I've
been through people don't know my
injuries people don't know what I'm
training for they're also not thinking
about it right no I also don't care now
that's another thing we do the outer
self is room and we think like what
happened to that guy like no they ain't
thinking that they're thinking about let
me do my seventh rep yeah that's all
they [__] think I'm right exactly
yeah yeah so so you think just I mean I
totally agree with you here just going
in going into the gym every day yeah
like in so those days with that six
months where you're not like you were
fueled by looking great being able to be
a beefy ass dude you lift all this stuff
yeah but now you're square one we're
going in there and you're like where's
my fuel like I don't feel great after I
leave the gym now but you still did it
every way so every day you wake up and
there's probably that other wolf that
says you don't go and don't know don't
know that yeah don't go but dude just I
think even whether we think it's a bad
work
or whatever I think just getting in
there and like it's a mental yeah like I
said if you're creating the momentum
yeah is what that's what drove me this I
went in there the first day it killed me
bro I'm one still went to the bathroom
like 10 times to just look myself in the
mirror and go dude are you like just
leave just leave what are you doing
you're not making any progress and I
would walk by looking around the week
dude dude and then every day it got
easier every single day got easier every
single day I've built more confidence
and it's crazy because when you look at
somebody that has been so confident for
so long you're like oh he's fine
like you know get back in the gym what
are you doing but my confidence was
absolutely destroyed because what I was
valuing at that time was strip for me my
body was taken from me what I thought
made me like it during that time it was
like all right who is Nate like who is
he okay he's he's got he's on a bike
he's he he's at quote-unquote he's a
badass right cuz he's running from the
cops and he's doing wheelies he's in
good shape
you know he's tatted you know like you
know night whenever girl yeah a night
Nike [__] I got the hard part you know
cut my hair [__]
comb over like dude bro the freshest the
freshest right and then it was all gone
the body was gone I don't have money to
get my haircut like I didn't have I had
my clothes that I had but I could I dude
I didn't wear a shoe on my right ankle I
couldn't wear a shoe for six months my
my foot was so swollen I would go to
court wearing one dress shoe and once
literate one slipper so I was like
alright who is Nate I had no idea I had
no idea
and so now where's my confidence right
so when I was confident in that in that
person that I was trying to be but then
when all that was gone and in one the
physical and every single thing that I
value was gone now Who am I so happy
where is yeah so yeah so it's like I was
being reborn it's like so how do you
have confidence when you don't know what
to be confident in right I gave no value
to anyone I didn't give value to the
woman I was with at the time I didn't
give value to my family like I was I was
a liability
my dad bailed me out of jail I don't
have any
like at that point I was like solo
because I didn't know what value I had
to bring I had no I had nothing to give
not even mentally physically anything
had nothing to give because the physical
is what I practiced you get good at what
you practice so if you practice the same
thing over and over and over again you
get good at it right but what if that's
gone then what any kidding be gone so
fast none one the second that one day
that you're biking it was gone
everything that I did everything that I
thought that I could give to the world
was gone mm-hmm you have to learn for
yourself yep would you really have to
offer
exactly and that's where that process
started yeah I mean but it took a long
time the Transformers crazy I know you
probably listen to Tony Robbins but Tony
Robbins always says he I was listening
in one of his speeches and he was
talking about everyone says it always
takes a long time to to change it
doesn't take a long time it takes a
split second it takes that one decision
but it's the events that lead up to the
change right so think about whenever you
decided to change it was that one day
you woke up and you were like dude what
today's the day right right right but it
was all the experiences that you had to
stack up in order to make that decision
right dude and that's how it is is we
think that where we need to go through
more stuff yeah we think that there's
something else like I'm gonna change
eventually I'm gonna get through this
eventually I'm gonna there's one day I'm
gonna wake up and that's gonna be the
day but little do you know life's been
sending you life rafts man every time
yeah I always I always tell people I
firmly believe that the universe are
like I said whoever it is you're gonna
keep learning the same lessons over and
over until you take from them what
you're supposed to take from them and
it's it was killer for me it was like it
was like my life was going in a circle I
was running in place I was going nowhere
because I refused to learn the lessons
that I was supposed to be learning
during those times right well now here
you are bro I mean I'm grateful man like
just like you're here for other people
because I just you know I care about
humanity just as much as you do I'm not
sure but I'm grateful you know in a
selfish way that you're here with me no
no so we get so happy get to spread this
one hurt
I kind of want to even going for a while
here I kind of want to round it out I if
you have anything else that you want to
bring around we definitely can but I
kind of an on that mirror thing and that
was just so profound to me so anybody
else who who isn't able to look in the
mirror you know and they can't turn the
lights on it's wrong like what uh I
don't know man do you have anything you
could you could tell those people like
you can't face themselves did they think
maybe they're the things that they've
done they think maybe they're the past
what their father told them what their
mother told yeah they look in the mirror
and they don't see that the person that
they know that they are that self that
true self-love that loving person I
think I think what takes people so long
and what took me so long is that one I
think it's the inability to see where
you really are like to be able to look
yourself in the mirror and assess
yourself you're basically when you hold
when you hold somebody accountable right
when you when you look at somebody and
they ask you you know how am I doing
with this how am i doing that and if
you're honest with them you might hurt
their feelings can you do that with
yourself right you know I'm saying then
that's what I had to do I I didn't I
couldn't look in the mirror and say
you're messing up like I couldn't look
in the mirror and say dude you you're
you have nothing to give anybody that's
hard that is hard to look at yourself
and and stay there too
it's hard to tell yourself all your
faults because that's what they are I
mean I it's not that they can't I think
a lot of people say I don't want to tell
myself when I'm doing that I don't like
because that's negative self-talk but if
you're not honest with yourself if you
can't self assess tell yourself where
you are and where you want to be you'll
never change and that's what I couldn't
do that's why I don't want to look at
the mirror because I didn't want to look
in the mirror and say this is what
you're doing and this is what you need
to be doing what you say with what you
want and what you want is not lining up
you say you want this I vote you know
I've always wanted a strong healthy
connection with a woman because I was
raised by my mother so I might you know
my dad was always there but my mom and I
were so close but I was like wow I want
to have a strong connection with a woman
how can I do that with the actions that
doing you can have one-night stands and
I'm a strong connection with a woman you
know I'm saying yeah I always said you
know I really want to be somebody that
people can look up to how I don't look
up to me why would anybody else look up
to me right but that's very hard it's
very very very hard to hold yourself
accountable and I find myself now that
I'm I feel like I'm in that in that mode
I do it every day like no matter how no
matter what time it is no matter where
I'm at if I need to talk to myself dude
I step away
I find a mirror dude I will literally
pull out my phone and pull up the camera
and do it and I'll be like dude where
are you where are you at right now are
you are you here are you at work are you
present like where's your are you giving
are you giving this what this needs what
it needs right now or or is your head
somewhere else I do that all the time I
wake up in the morning
yeah and the first thing I do after I do
my routine I read all my stuff I get up
and I go look in the mirror I'm like
what's going on today or do it if I need
that positive reinforcement I look at
the man I'm like yo you're a bro yeah
you got this you know who you are a
monster yeah but people don't do that
and that's the thing is like I don't
want to sound like I'm like I'm into
myself but that's what it takes like who
is gonna tell me I'm a beast of I don't
know you have to see the thing is where
we do have a weird thing where people
misinterpret the word eagle and they
misinterpret like because a lot of us
cast ourselves up yeah out of us on
social media we don't even realize we do
it but we ask for compliments because of
that we're so afraid of being that
person and making sure we're not doing
that yes we avoid gasps and ourselves up
Oh Leon against ourselves I know you
have a lot of this negative self-talk
that has become normal debt has become
okay to just joke about yourself an
insult every two seconds I'm not okay no
it's not because that that it changes
your emotions yeah like if and I think
also to like I said I think it's the
hardest parts of your self development
is being honest with yourself and saying
that like a lot of people will use that
negative self-talk so they don't have to
live up to that expectation they don't
have to fail if I say I'm going to fail
it's okay if I do but
I say that I'm gonna succeed and I don't
then I'm a failure or if you distract
yourself concentrating on everybody
else's failure exactly are they our ego
loves to do that we find where we're not
fulfilling ourself in other people and
then we attack them about it you know
yeah and that's why I'd like to gem so
much too because there's mirrors
everywhere
so everywhere I go I'm like are you are
you are you I don't like wasting my time
yeah that's a big thing for me I feel
like just given the experience that I
have a couple recent passings Zack tech
well I know you're new Zack Zack and I
were really close friends it was really
hard for me and my grandma you can't get
time back and I realized that in in
losing those people I realized that you
can't get time back and so now I'm being
on my time I hate wasting time so if I'm
at the gym and if I'm not just giving it
everything I've got I'm like dude are
you wasting your time
do not waste your own time your time is
so valuable you know I'll be at home you
know or in the car like when I go park
somewhere I'll like look at my phone for
a couple minutes for our walk in I might
dude you're wasting your time yeah not
waste your time right with it with the
most mindless stuff you pull yourself
out of it you're like what the heck was
I doing I just follow an Amazon ad on
Facebook what not happening and then
you're on this trail right yeah and the
next you know 10 minutes has gone by and
so that's a huge thing for me and I
think the self-talk is what changed the
mirror for me is what was able to help
me turn the lights on was the self-talk
I replaced it because I used to tell
myself like dude you can't do this you
can do that every day
I never even spoke to people because I
was always telling myself what I was
doing wrong I was talking to myself
right you you're so caught up with me in
yourself that you can't even say it was
crazy yeah I wasn't I wasn't being I
wasn't operating what I was supposed to
be doing I wasn't you know being a
leader I totally meant to be a leader
I'm meant to lead people I meant to
change people's lives and I couldn't
even do that because I was so negative
with myself like and that's what I tell
people always is like if you don't care
about yourself and what you're doing you
can't care about anybody else
absolutely the biggest thing that I've
had to learn with all this [__] for me
man like I was thinking that I was like
putting you know I'm helping people I'm
doing all that I can
like I don't have any love for myself
but I'll give it to other people you
know and that was like keeping me
hanging on for a while with whatever
[__] I was going on in my head but
like ultimately the answer to me helping
other people is self-love oh I didn't
have so I wouldn't have this podcast if
I didn't have this podcast this many
people wouldn't be able to listen to it
and hopefully get something a little bit
good some amount of I don't have time to
respond to every single individual
person like it's just self-love is what
makes change your life yeah it's my
liable to do something yeah it gives a
power yeah exactly
it's definitely that's what changed my
life too because I like I said that
whole mirror thing it wouldn't be if I
didn't start caring about myself and
care about what I was doing taking pride
in what I was doing and being able to
hold myself accountable right like I use
that thing all the time now I love that
all the time it's like dude are you you
know if I tell my I'm honest with myself
like you know you didn't really get a
whole lot done today like you know you
said you want to do this and I'm again
it's with the time and I like to be
especially with myself I like to hold
myself accountable like to be a man of
my word like if I tell myself I'm gonna
do something I was like dude you took
you said you're Indian you didn't do it
you didn't even attempt to do that like
what did you do today you messed around
I just I think it's so important I dude
I totally talk to myself all the time
like I'll be outside talking to myself
like people think I'm crazy at the gym
when I like speak out loud and people
are like whoa what's this guy doing I'll
run and I'll run at night and I run up
this hill and I'll be screaming and
people are like running but like you're
driving by me like he's like what did I
do that with it when I'm doing like
trail running yeah I literally I have
like a mantra just one that I that stuck
on my head from you - yeah I'm healthy
I'm wealthy and wise yes it puts me in a
trance / I mean agreement that as I'm
running through trails do it and the
best part is you forget what you're
doing yeah and you're just going so hard
yeah and you know it whatever you're
saying to yourself you know it and so
that's the thing is it's not weird it's
not corny it's not dorky you'll not be
ashamed don't do any where you're at in
life whether you're at the gym whether
you're by yourself whether your mom's
trying to sleep you know maybe keep it
down yeah talk to yourself man talk to
yourself this wall that people may see
this wall started with me sitting
crisscross applesauce on the floor and
this like crusty basement that
then I would just partying and I just
started writing my thoughts like whether
that's talking out loud to yourself
whether that's listening to things and I
call that's a good thing that I just
heard a new job down it's a constant
reminder yeah that's what this has
that's what the hashtags are what are
your hashtags lamed up man so the most
important ones but that wasn't [__] that
wasn't that wasn't [__] every everybody
thinks that it was like cocky because I
started doing it with the bike stuff
right again
with the video they just dropped today
look me up on YouTube Maxine ate the
whole story from that wasn't [__] is on
the video today
everyone thinks that it came from a win
like I did a trick and I was like oh
that wasn't [__] or I got a job and I
was like oh that wasn't [__] it came
from the L it came from me battling I I
was at a point in my life where I didn't
know if I wanted to be here anymore I
didn't know if I want to live I didn't
know if I wanted to keep moving and I
made it through that and and I made it
through the injury I made it through the
mental part of the injury the physical
part of the injury the mental part was
the worst and after I got back on my
feet I was in the gym I started riding
dude I was just killing it like I was a
monster like I came back like so like a
caged animal and I was like one day I
was like thinking like you know I'd been
done riding loaded on my bike go home
sit on the couch and I was like thinking
about you know the previous times and
everything and I was like dude you you
made it through all that stuff that you
thought that you weren't gonna make it
through you did I was like what is that
I was like that wasn't [__] like that
was not [__] was crazy it's now whatever
it's gonna happen in your life it's like
that's what I'll be like oh I needed
that because I was really not ready for
this crazy yes yeah well that was crazy
it's amazing man mental preparation
right and and I use it but now I use it
for everything I use it with the winds
to like when I'm at the gym and I'm
pushing myself so hard I use it as a
current - like I'll be lifted I'm like
this ain't [__] this ain't [__] this
ain't [__] over and over and over and
over and over again like and then when
I'm done I'm like damn that wasn't [__]
like you got more like you can do and
it's not see that's the thing is it's
not negative self-talk cuz negative
self-talk is toxic and terrible yeah but
with the way the way you're using it is
like no because I know myself in my
heart that I'm capable more yeah I can
do that and it's gonna feel good when I
do that
yeah that wasn't [__] just getting
started just give you for me cuz I you
know I was doing you know I was like
mentally changing physically changing my
riding was going to a whole new level my
life was going to hone their level and
I'm like dude I got so much morning me
I'm just getting started like just wait
like just wait I think those are the two
biggest ones for me and then is that all
you got all the time it's hard you know
dude I gotta tell you a story I hate to
drag this out but I don't know how hit
me with this story I have a friend of a
friend which I which I won't name his
mom is in her 60s she's in her early 60s
she has stage 3 breast cancer for the
third time officially she is a fighter
bro she's a fighter she's the most
beautiful woman in the entire world she
calls me and I'm you know I'm on my
voicemail I missed a call right actually
one voicemail I answer
she's like Nate I want you to know that
I'm on my way to renew my gym membership
and it has everything to do with your
video because I looked at myself today
and I'm proud I'm about to like it's
just hit me just melted a little bit um
and she says I looked at myself and I
said is that really all you got and she
said I looked at myself and the answer
was no she brought she's a cancer
survivor like do you know what that does
for me
road you know what that does for me yeah
like I'm like I'm like let's go yeah I'm
like somebody put me on a stage bro like
that is that's what I need like that
that is a the biggest payment that I
could ever receive like I touched
somebody that has a life-threatening
illness yeah she got off of her
brother's stuff that we deal with is
nothing compared to that right she said
that you inspired her and you're like to
go to this to Jesus to go to the gym
yeah cuz she said I tell my son eight I
tell myself all the time
is that really all you got is that
really hard because it's not because
there is and I think that that one was a
little later that that wasn't shits been
there for a while so for like four years
but
was a new one and the fact that that
story I'm able to tell that story
because that hashtag is unreal for me
bro unreal yeah so I kill the feelings
yeah yeah I'm in the fields right now
that's beautiful anything thing wrong
with that dude so so your hashtag so
you're gonna keep going with your
hashtags yes let's just we can round it
out but what's your what's your what's
what's next for nasty Nate man like what
what are you been let's just round about
what we've been working on here what
have you been what's next man I'm gonna
start volunteering my time I'm gonna
start speaking speaking has always
anybody who's a speaker motivational
speaker while at me I'm sure yeah just I
mean you could just go back and forth
you need something a little more
specific yeah I feel like you're pretty
good at picking up what you need to do
100% I feel like yeah it's always been a
gift of mine I'm really really really
observant I can I can sit with people
without them talking and kind of feel
them I feel like that's so important and
I feel like it's gonna be important for
my for my speaking too but I really I
just want to start speaking it's always
been so hard for me I always been I wore
that mask like we talked about for so
long I was so embarrassed of who I
actually was that I was afraid to be
myself so every time out you know I'd
record these videos like they're out
there outside so if someone walks by and
I'm like I'm like dude I'm almost like
what's his camera doing here
like like what is this like googling
who's talking I'm not talking it I can't
we do I think yeah and the process of
starting that YouTube channel was so
long for me because I'll go go to the
park go to wherever try to record this
video couldn't get it done couldn't get
it done I pick up if someone walked by
to pick up the camera go somewhere else
there's people everywhere like it's like
at this point are we done for in New
York dude I would I would never make it
but I'm finally getting the point where
I feel comfortable like I'm like okay
this is who you are
like you don't want to can not that I'm
grateful for everything in my life right
now including the job that I work I'm so
grateful over that but it's not the end
game for me right if I don't break
outside of that mold
I don't get close to that edge like
that's what I call it's the edge like if
you're not I'm like I'm I feel like I'm
right on the edge of elevation is what I
call it right on the edge of elevation
I'm right there if I don't step over
that line I'm never gonna make the
impact I want and I think that's what
took me so long is I always dreamed so
big and I'm like why would I ever think
that that's gonna work and now that I'm
like it you just do it you do it and and
like you know I hate it I hate the touch
on the the feedback that I get because I
know I I would say that I I want to
build it you know do it without that
positive reinforcement but I think you
know it's part of it's all part of the
process that's all part of the process
so we're tribal beings you know like we
want accept 100% to know that what we've
been putting our heart and soul in you
have people it reaches significant in
really honest because I'm saying when
some when someone tells me it's not what
I'm going for but when they message
motivating man it's so motivating yeah I
just want to you know be significant and
so I think I'm gonna start speaking I'm
I started volunteering my time anywhere
like it dude old folks homes like
wherever I can go to to relay a message
I'm very I think that was the creativity
with the camera and the photo editing
the video editing it was all kind of
like a step for me to find my creative
side my mom's always been creative my
grandma was a painter like you know I
come from a creative family my cousin
customizes sneakers like a comfort most
creative family so that now this is my
creativity's with words like as far as
how how was i how I can relate certain
experiences that I have to your life
like you know like I said with what's
working out and the bike and and what
it's done for me it's all the bike is
like a metaphor in itself for me and so
I think being able to connect things
that people can relate to and say it in
a positive way and a positive message is
that's that's really what I'm going for
and that's what you know I hope one day
I'm not gonna use that word hope one day
it's a matter of damn time but Monday
one day I'm gonna get paid to speak and
that's what I'm gonna do for a living
yeah
for the rest of my life I absolutely
agree I think that you're gonna be
someone who's going to help a lot of
people I mean I think your truth and
your your perseverance and your strength
and I get honestly just badass will to
not give up really it's great man it's
very inspiring very inspiring to see and
obviously to just like talk to you about
it I love when up to me yeah I love
sharing my story dude I think it's kind
of like I call it like the sauce like
you can't mix the sauce and have the
sauce and not give it away I think
everybody's story is important and I
think someone has either gone through is
going through or is going to go through
something that I went through and so if
I don't share it they're not gonna make
it through they might not right yeah my
she always says like who would you need
when you were 16 like man like if I
could get myself my little punk ass and
my little tight pants my red hair - just
listen down you know don't talk to
responsibility like I've got this thing
you help these talents like nope so yeah
just if you can get people to listen and
believe in themselves and nothing that's
what you're doing right now so I'm super
pumped for your future I'm people to see
what happens I'm super pumped for all
the people are gonna help thank you so
much bro yeah when I bro fist pump one
more time and I appreciate you I don't
care I love podcasts out everybody have
a good rest of your day stay off your
phone and breathe in some fresh air
today
you